(function(){function c(o){l[m].classList.remove("active-slide"),l[o].classList.add("active-slide"),m=o,j.style.display=0===m?"none":"inline-block",m===l.length-1?(k.style.display="none",i.style.display="inline-block"):(k.style.display="inline-block",i.style.display="none")}var f=[{question:"193.\tA local doctor serving 1,700 urban population is writing an annual report and analyzing morbidity of the population of the site. There were 600 cases of acute diseases, 280 cases of newly discovered chronic diseases, 650 exacerbations of chronic diseases, 850 cases of diseases discovered during routine examinations, 2 cases of mortality from diseases. How many cases of diseases belong to primary morbidity?",answers:{a:" \t 2,380",b:" \t 600",c:" \t 1,530",d:" \t 850",e:"  \t 880"},correctAnswer:"e"},{question:"194.\tA local doctor serving 1,700 urban population is writing an annual report and analyzing morbidity of the population of the site. There were 600 cases of acute diseases, 280 cases of newly discovered chronic diseases, 650 exacerbations of chronic diseases, 850 cases of diseases discovered during routine examinations, 2 cases of mortality from diseases. How many cases of diseases belong to general morbidity?",answers:{a:" \t 880",b:" \t 600",c:"  \t 1,530",d:" \t 850",e:" \t 2,380"},correctAnswer:"c"},{question:"195.\tA local doctor serving 1,700 urban population is writing an annual report and analyzing morbidity of the population of the site. There were 600 cases of acute diseases, 280 cases of newly discovered chronic diseases, 650 exacerbations of chronic diseases, 850 cases of diseases discovered during routine examinations, 2 cases of mortality from diseases. How many cases of diseases belong to exhaustive morbidity?",answers:{a:" \t 1,530",b:" \t 600",c:" \t 880",d:"  \t 2,380",e:" \t 850"},correctAnswer:"d"},{question:"196.\tA local doctor serving 1,700 urban population is writing an annual report and analyzing morbidity of the population of the site. There were 600 cases of acute diseases, 280 cases of newly discovered chronic diseases, 650 exacerbations of chronic diseases, 850 cases of diseases discovered during routine examinations, 2 cases of mortality from diseases. How do you calculate the index of primary morbidity?",answers:{a:" \t (600+280+650) / 1,700 ? 1,000",b:"  \t (600+280) / 1,700 ? 1,000",c:" \t (600+280+650+850) / 1,700 ? 1,000",d:" \t (600+280) / (600+280+650+850) ? 1,000",e:" \t (180+650) / (600+280+650+850) ? 1,000"},correctAnswer:"b"},{question:"197.\tA local doctor serving 1,700 urban population is writing an annual report and analyzing morbidity of the population of the site. There were 600 cases of acute diseases, 280 cases of newly discovered chronic diseases, 650 exacerbations of chronic diseases, 850 cases of diseases discovered during routine examinations, 2 cases of mortality from diseases. How do you calculate the index of general morbidity?",answers:{a:"  \t (600+280+650) / 1,700 ? 1,000",b:" \t (600+280+650+850) / 1,700 ? 1,000",c:" \t (600+280) / (600+280+650+850) ? 1,000",d:" \t (600+280) / 1,700 ? 1,000",e:" \t (180+650) / (600+280+650+850) ? 1,000"},correctAnswer:"a"},{question:"198.\tA local doctor serving 1,700 urban population is writing an annual report and analyzing morbidity of the population of the site. There were 600 cases of acute diseases, 280 cases of newly discovered chronic diseases, 650 exacerbations of chronic diseases, 850 cases of diseases discovered during routine examinations, 2 cases of mortality from diseases. How do you calculate the index of exhaustive morbidity?",answers:{a:" \t (600+280) / (600+280+650+850) ? 1,000",b:" \t (600+280+650) / 1,700 ? 1,000",c:"  \t (600+280+650+850) / 1,700 ? 1,000",d:" \t (600+280) / 1,700 ? 1,000",e:" \t (180+650) / (600+280+650+850) ? 1,000"},correctAnswer:"c"},{question:"199.\tWhile examining a patient, a local therapist suspected breast cancer. When and where should the doctor send the corresponding registration document in this case?",answers:{a:"\t Within 3 days, sanitary-epidemiologic center",b:" \t Within 12 hours, in oncologic dispensary",c:" \t Within 12 hours, infectious diseases hospital",d:" \t Urgent hospitalization in oncologic dispensary",e:"   \t Within 3 days, in oncologic dispensary"},correctAnswer:"e"},{question:"200.\tWhile examining a patient, a local therapist suspected schizophrenia. When and where should the doctor send the corresponding registration document in this case?",answers:{a:" \t Within 12 hours, psychoneurological dispensary",b:"  \t Within 3 days, psychoneurological dispensary",c:" \t Within 12 hours, surgical department of hospital",d:" \t Urgent hospitalization in a psychoneurological dispensary",e:" \t Within 3 days, sanitary-epidemiologic center"},correctAnswer:"b"},{question:"201.\tSyphilis was discovered in a pregnant woman on observation in maternity clinic. When and where should the doctor send the corresponding registration document in this case?",answers:{a:" \t Within 3 days, sanitary-epidemiologic center",b:" \t Within 12 hours, dermatovenereological dispensary",c:" \t Within 12 hours, surgical department of hospital",d:" \t Urgent hospitalization in a dermatovenereological dispensary",e:"  \t Within 3 days, dermatovenereological dispensary"},correctAnswer:"e"},{question:"202.\tGonorrhea was discovered in a pregnant woman on observation in maternity clinic. When and where should the doctor send the corresponding registration document in this case?",answers:{a:" \t Within 12 hours, surgical department of hospital",b:" \t Within 12 hours, dermatovenereological dispensary",c:" \t Within 3 days, sanitary-epidemiologic center",d:"  \t Within 3 days, dermatovenereological dispensary",e:" \t Urgent hospitalization in a dermatovenereological dispensary"},correctAnswer:"d"},{question:"203.\tWhile examining a patient, a lung specialist suspected active tuberculosis. When and where should the doctor send the corresponding registration document in this case?",answers:{a:"  \t Within 3 days, antituberculous dispensary",b:" \t Within 12 hours, antituberculous dispensary",c:" \t Within 12 hours, surgical department of hospital",d:" \t Urgent hospitalization in an antituberculous dispensary",e:" \t Within 3 days, sanitary-epidemiologic center"},correctAnswer:"a"},{question:"204.\tWhile examining a patient, an ophthalmologist suspected trachoma. When and where should the doctor send the corresponding registration document in this case?",answers:{a:" \t Within 12 hours, surgical department of hospital",b:" \t Within 12 hours, dermatovenereological dispensary",c:" \t Within 3 days, sanitary-epidemiologic center",d:"  \t Within 3 days, dermatovenereological dispensary",e:" \t Urgent hospitalization in a dermatovenereological dispensary"},correctAnswer:"d"},{question:"205.\tWhile examining a patient. a family doctor suspected trichophytosis. When and where should the doctor send the corresponding registration document in this case?",answers:{a:"  \t Within 3 days, dermatovenereological dispensary",b:" \t Within 12 hours, dermatovenereological dispensary",c:" \t Within 3 days, sanitary-epidemiologic center",d:" \t Within 12 hours, surgical department of hospital",e:" \t Urgent hospitalization in a dermatovenereological dispensary"},correctAnswer:"a"},{question:"206.\tWhile examining a patient, a family doctor suspected microsporia. When and where should the doctor send the corresponding registration document in this case?",answers:{a:" \t Within 12 hours, surgical department of hospital",b:" \t Within 12 hours, dermatovenereological dispensary",c:" \t Within 3 days, sanitary-epidemiologic center",d:"  \t Within 3 days, dermatovenereological dispensary",e:" \t Urgent hospitalization in a dermatovenereological dispensary"},correctAnswer:"d"},{question:"207.\tWhat is gross-factor of population reproduction?",answers:{a:" \t Number of children born by the woman throughout the fertile period (15-49 years)",b:" \t Number of the people living in the country in given year",c:"  \t Number of the girls born by the woman aged 15-49 years",d:" \t Number of the girls born by the woman aged 15-49 years, reached the fertile age",e:" \t Birth rate \u2013 death rate"},correctAnswer:"c"},{question:"208.\tNet-factor of population procreations equals 0,7, gross-factor \u2013 1,0, total coefficient of reproduction of the population \u2013 1,9. How estimate process of reproduction of the population?",answers:{a:"  \t The progressive",b:" \t The narrowed",c:" \t The dilated",d:" \t The stationary",e:" \t The regressive"},correctAnswer:"a"},{question:"209.\tLevel of a general death rate is 11 \u2030, a mortality rate of babies \u2013 14 \u2030, prevalence of chronic not epidemic diseases are characteristic for type of a pathology of the countries:",answers:{a:" \t Economically developed",b:"  \t European continent",c:" \t Insufficiently economically developed",d:" \t The developing",e:" \t American continent"},correctAnswer:"b"},{question:"210.\tIn the city of D birth rate level constitutes 25,3 \u2030, a general death rate \u2013 16,3 \u2030, death rate of babies \u2013 23,1 \u2030. Estimate to levels of the specified indices.",answers:{a:" \t Birth rate \u2013 average, death rate \u2013 high, death rate of babies \u2013 low",b:" \t Birth rate \u2013 low, death rate \u2013 average, death rate of babies \u2013 low",c:" \t Birth rate \u2013 low, death rate \u2013 high, death rate of babies \u2013 high",d:"  \t Birth rate \u2013 high, death rate \u2013 high, death rate of babies \u2013 low",e:" \t Birth rate \u2013 average, death rate \u2013 high, death rate of babies \u2013 high"},correctAnswer:"d"},{question:"211.\tConstant population shift belongs to indices:",answers:{a:"  \t Population statics",b:" \t Demographic load",c:" \t Natural movement of the population",d:" \t Mechanic movement of the population",e:" \t Population viability"},correctAnswer:"a"},{question:"212.\tIn region N because of favourable climatic, ecological and social and economic conditions the augmentation of number of the pensioners who have moved to region from other corners of the country is noted. State administration, having estimated reserve capacity of region, has entered a series of privileges. Specify what kind of mechanic movement of the population occurs in region.",answers:{a:"  \t Population seasonal migration",b:" \t Constant population shift",c:" \t Pendulum population shift",d:" \t Population emigration",e:" \t Population immigration"},correctAnswer:"a"},{question:"213.\tExpectant mother \u041F, age of 25 years, with a normal current of pregnancy in 34 weeks has got to a road accident. For the third day she has died of the received traumas. What is death rate kind?",answers:{a:"  General death rate",b:" \t Early neonatal death rate",c:" \t Perinatal death rate",d:" \t \t Maternal death rate",e:" \t Neonatal death rate"},correctAnswer:"d"},{question:"214.\tNecessary data gathers for reception of the information on natural movement of population. How the given research is called?",answers:{a:" \t The continuous flowing",b:"  \t The selective simultaneous",c:" \t The continuous simultaneous",d:" \t The selective flowing",e:" \t The basic file"},correctAnswer:"b"},{question:"215.\tPsychological specific features of behaviour characterise:",answers:{a:"  \t Level of living",b:" \t Quality of life",c:" \t Style of life",d:" \t Way of life",e:" \t Healthy conduct of life"},correctAnswer:"a"},{question:"216.\tIn structure of population of region D the share of people aged 0-14 years has constituted 15%, the share of the population aged 15-49 years \u2013 69%, share of people aged 50 years and older has constituted 16%, including share of people older 60 years has constituted 4%. Average life expectancy constitutes 67 years. Estimate members of the population which characterises the given demographic situation.",answers:{a:" \t Regressive content of the population, low rate of an ageing of the population",b:" \t Regressive content of the population, appreciable rate of an ageing of the population",c:" \t Stationary content of the population, moderate rate of an ageing of the population",d:" \t Progressive content of the population, moderate rate of an ageing of the population",e:"  \t Regressive content of the population, moderate rate of an ageing of the population"},correctAnswer:"e"},{question:"217.\tOne of the important indices which characterize population\u2019s state of health is life expectancy. What age index of mortality influences average life expectancy most of all?",answers:{a:"  \t Mortality of babies",b:" \t Mortality of children older than 1 year",c:" \t Mortinatality",d:" \t Mortality at working age",e:" \t Mortality in the elderly"},correctAnswer:"a"},{question:"218.\tAt metallurgical complex of a big industrial city 230 people work, living in the countryside and spending 2 hours on traveling there and back daily. What is the migration of workers?",answers:{a:" \t Daily migration",b:" \t Constant migration",c:" \t Seasonal migration",d:"  \t Pendulum migration",e:" \t Monthly migration"},correctAnswer:"d"},{question:"219.\tWhat document needs to be constituted, if the child was born during stay of mother in a train?",answers:{a:" \t The birth medical certificate",b:" \t The certificate of birth",c:"  \t The medical certificate on stay of the child under medical institution examination",d:" \t The act about birth of the child",e:" \t The health certificate on birth"},correctAnswer:"c"},{question:"220.\tNewborn girl (mass 3000 g, growth of 51 cm) has died for 9 day of life owing to the expressed congenital pathology incompatible with life. What is death rate kind?",answers:{a:"\t   Perinatal death rate",b:" \t Early neonatal death rate",c:" \t General death rate",d:"    Late neonatal death rate",e:" \t Postneonatal death rate"},correctAnswer:"d"},{question:"221.\tThe ratio of gross migration to the average number of the population on some territory called:",answers:{a:" \t Gross migration",b:" \t Efficiency ratio of migrations",c:" \t Net migration",d:" \t Intensity factor of net migration",e:"  \t Coefficient mobility of the population"},correctAnswer:"e"},{question:"222.\tIn the area R. the infant mortality from perinatal causes accounted 7 cases per 1000 population. Which of the following indicators characterizing the level of infant mortality?",answers:{a:"  \t Intensive index",b:" \t Parameter of correlation",c:" \t Extensive index",d:" \t Parameter of visualization",e:" \t Standardized"},correctAnswer:"a"},{question:"223.\tWhat method of demographic analysis characterized by obtaining the necessary information through surveys, interviews, etc?",answers:{a:" \t Mathematical modeling",b:" \t Cartographical",c:" \t Statistical",d:"  \t Sociological",e:" \t Empirical"},correctAnswer:"d"},{question:"224.\tWhich parameters belong to the category of absolute values?",answers:{a:" \t The proportion of extramarital births",b:" \t The distribution of births by order of birth",c:" \t Number of births per 1 woman of reproductive age",d:"  \t Death babies",e:" \t Natural increase of the population"},correctAnswer:"d"},{question:"225.\tThe birth-rate refers to indicators of:",answers:{a:" \t Mechanical population movement",b:" \t Static of the population",c:" \t Demographic burden",d:"  \t Natural population movement",e:" \t Population viability"},correctAnswer:"d"},{question:"226.\tA component of the concept of \xABgeneral morbidity\xBB is:",answers:{a:"  \t Earlier known chronic diseases",b:" \t Diseases which deaths have led",c:" \t Physical development",d:" \t Diseases discovered during occupational examinations",e:" \t Morbidity of invalids"},correctAnswer:"a"},{question:"227.\tAt inspection of a patient local therapist suspected breast cancer. When and where in this case should the doctor send corresponding registration document?",answers:{a:" \t Urgent hospitalisation in an oncologic dispensary",b:" \t Within 12 hours, to oncologic dispensary",c:" \t Within 12 hours, to infectious diseases hospital",d:"  \t Within 3 days, in an oncologic dispensary",e:" \t Within 3 days, in sanitary-and-epidemiologic centre"},correctAnswer:"d"},{question:"228.\tMain grouping principle of the International classification of diseases, traumas and causes of death is",answers:{a:"  \t Common aetiology, pathogenesis and localisation of diseases",b:" \t Common aetiology and clinical implications of diseases",c:" \t Common pathogenesis and pathomorphologic attributes of diseases",d:" \t Alphabetic principle",e:" \t Clinical-morphological implications of diseases"},correctAnswer:"a"},{question:"229.\tWhat morbidity is subject to special accounting?",answers:{a:" \t Morbidity of diseases of digestive organs.",b:" \t Morbidity of diseases of system of a circulation.",c:" \t Morbidity of diseases of respiratory organs.",d:"  \t Morbidity of acute infectious diseases.",e:" \t Morbidity of diseases of nervous system and sense organs."},correctAnswer:"d"},{question:"230.\tOften sick people are those who within current year had etiologically related diseases:",answers:{a:"  \t 4 times and more",b:" \t 2 times and more",c:" \t 3 times and more",d:" \t 5 times and more",e:" \t 6 times and more"},correctAnswer:"a"},{question:"231.\tTherapist is entrusted to carry out analysis of morbidity of the population on his site. Which of the sources of study of morbidity provide the most complete accounting of acute diseases?",answers:{a:" \t Population hospitalisation",b:" \t Specially organised research",c:" \t Causes of death",d:"  \t Calls in ambulatory-polyclinic institutions",e:" \t Routine inspections"},correctAnswer:"d"},{question:"232.\tPatient B died at home. Prosector established the diagnosis: combined cirrhosis, bleeding from varicose expanded veins of esophagus. Acute posthemorrhagic anaemia. Chronic non-obstructive bronchitis. What disease will be written in the \u201CMedical death certificate\u201D in point 4.1 (cause of death)?",answers:{a:"  Acute posthemorrhagic anaemia, bleeding from varicose expanded veins.",b:" \t Bleeding from varicose expanded veins of esophagus.",c:" \t Combined cirrhosis",d:" \t Chronic non-obstructive bronchitis.",e:" \t \t Acute posthemorrhagic anaemia."},correctAnswer:"e"},{question:"233.\tMost objective diagnosis is the basic advantage of study of morbidity on:",answers:{a:" \t Calls",b:"  \t Data about causes of death",c:" \t Medical inspections",d:" \t Population hospitalisation",e:" \t Correlation analysis"},correctAnswer:"b"},{question:"234.\tPrimary prophylaxis of influence of risk factors on origin and development of major chronic non-epidemic diseases belongs to \u2026 section of complex prophylaxis of CND:",answers:{a:" \t Sanitary-educational",b:" \t Social and economic",c:"  \t Sanitary-and-hygienic",d:" \t Organizational",e:" \t Treatment-and-prophylactic"},correctAnswer:"c"},{question:"235.\tFamily doctor serving 1100 urban population, in his annual statement analyzes morbidity of the population of the site. 300 cases were of acute diseases, chronic discovered for the first time \u2013 180 cases, complications of chronic diseases \u2013 450 cases, discovered during routine inspections \u2013 550 cases of diseases, mortalities from diseases \u2013 2. How to calculate index of exhaustive morbidity?",answers:{a:" \t (300+180+450+550) / 1100 ? 1000",b:" \t  (300+180+450) / 1100 ? 1000",c:" \t (300+180) / (300+180+450+550) ? 1000",d:" \t (300+180) / 1100 ? 1000",e:"  \t (180+450) / (300+180+450+550) ? 1000"},correctAnswer:"e"},{question:"236.\tShare of working people which were not sick during a calendar year is called:",answers:{a:"  Indices of health of the population",b:" \t Demographic load",c:" \t Pathological rate",d:" \t 3rd health group",e:" \t \t Health index"},correctAnswer:"e"},{question:"237.\tThere is data about number of workers, number of cases of diseases with temporal disability at factory H. What index can be calculated?",answers:{a:" \t Share of those who are sick",b:"  \t Number of cases of disability on 100 working",c:" \t Number of days of disability on 100 working",d:" \t Structure of cases and days of disability by separate diseases",e:" \t Average duration of one case of disability by all diseases"},correctAnswer:"b"},{question:"238.\tIn district N are developed: in district N \u2014 the central regional hospital, in settlement of city type \u0421 \u2014 regional hospital. Which function of these institutions of public health services considerably differ?",answers:{a:" \t Rendering of the specialised is ambulatory-polyclinic care to the district population",b:" \t Rendering of the primary care to the population of the locale and sites",c:"  \t Organizational-methodical job management of treatment-and-prophylactic institutions of district",d:" \t Rendering of the specialised stationary care to the district population",e:" \t Maintenance fast and an acute management the district population"},correctAnswer:"c"}],g=document.getElementById("quiz"),h=document.getElementById("results"),i=document.getElementById("submit");(function(){var o=[];f.forEach((p,q)=>{var r=[];for(letter in p.answers)r.push(`<label>
             <input type="radio" name="question${q}" value="${letter}">
              ${letter} :
              ${p.answers[letter]}
           </label>`);o.push(`<div class="slide">
           <div class="question"> ${p.question} </div>
           <div class="answers"> ${r.join("")} </div>
         </div>`)}),g.innerHTML=o.join("")})();var j=document.getElementById("previous"),k=document.getElementById("next"),l=document.querySelectorAll(".slide");let m=0;c(0),i.addEventListener("click",function(){var o=g.querySelectorAll(".answers");let p=0;f.forEach((q,r)=>{var s=o[r],t=`input[name=question${r}]:checked`,u=(s.querySelector(t)||{}).value;u===q.correctAnswer?(p++,o[r].style.color="lightgreen"):o[r].style.color="red"}),h.innerHTML=`${p} out of ${f.length}`}),j.addEventListener("click",function(){c(m-1)}),k.addEventListener("click",function(){c(m+1)})})();
